# **Devin Lehmacher**

308 108th Ave NE, Apt. C213, Bellevue, WA 98004 djl329@cornell.edu • +1 (864) 722–3014 • github.com/lehmacdj

**SUMMARY** 

Self motivated software engineer with proven commitment to programming in Haskell. 2+ years of industry experience developing concurrent cloud services that comprise Microsoft's Azure AD identity platform. Strong theoretical background in functional programming and programming language theory from university courses.

**EDUCATION** 

# Cornell University, Ithaca, NY

Aug 2015 — May 2019

Bachelors of Arts in Computer Science

■ Cumulative GPA: 3.611

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Microsoft, Azure AD, Software Engineer II

Aug 2019 — Present

Design, prototype, develop, instrument, and test new features for backend service

Redmond, WA

- Monitor and analyze metrics and logs for service to ensure quality of service
- Debug and fix bugs impacting customers' authentication
- Participate in regular security and privacy reviews to ensure compliance
- Coordinated sub-team of 4 through transition to service's general availability
- Prototyped and completed Cosmos DB migration to handle over 5x of the original load
- Integrated Polly, a C# fault handling library, with an existing cloud service

## **Cornell University**, Teaching Assistant

Feb 2016 — May 2019

Ithaca, NY

- Taught weekly sections with 25 students
  Held weekly office hours to help students understand the course material
- Answered students' questions on Piazza, during office hours, and after class
- Helped test, create, and plan future assignments
- Graded assignments and exams, giving students helpful feedback

## **Microsoft**, Software Engineering Intern

May 2018 — Aug 2018

Designed a microservice architecture for a new cloud service

Redmond, WA

- Worked with team to determine what the service's critical features are
- Implemented a prototype of those features using Microsoft Service Fabric and Azure

#### Itron Inc., Intern

Jun 2017 — Aug 2017

• Created a dashboard to visualize available space for testing electrical meters

Oconee, SC

- Utilized Transact-SQL to collect data for the dashboard
- Built and deployed reports to Sharepoint using Microsoft Reporting Services

#### **PROJECTS**

## Xi Compiler, compiler for a simple C-like programming language

- Collaborated with a group of 3 other students over the course of a semester
- Implemented parser, type checker, optimizer, and x86 assembly code generation
- Added object oriented features while maintaining backwards compatibility

### **Graph System**, Haskell knowlege graph console application

- Extensively uses algebraic effects via polysemy library to make code more testable
- Made several JSON schema migrations, requiring careful planning for backwards compatibility

# **Open Source**

- Submit pull requests and bug reports, contribute to feature discussions
- Made git credential daemon conform to the XDG directory specification
- Added missing library functions to Haskell libraries

## PortOS, minimal operating system running on a MIPS virtual machine

- Implemented multithreading with preemption, and TCP and UDP analogs
- Learned how to navigate and write a moderately sized (10,000 lines) C code base

## Interpreters, interpreters and type checkers for variety of languages

- a subset Scheme, System F, Calculus of Constructions, OCalf (a subset of OCaml)
- Wrote a library to abstract common tasks that arose when implementing interpreters

**SKILLS** 

Fluent: Haskell, C#, shell scripting, Microsoft Azure, Git, Vim, Linux

Familiar: REST, C, Java, OCaml, Rust, SQL, Python, Nix